Stanislav Khrapov

CONTACT Information Frankfurt am Main, Germany Email: khrapovs@gmail.com Web: khrapovs.github.io

Personal Statement Stanislav Khrapov is an Assistant Professor of Finance at the New Economic School in Moscow, Russia. His area of specialization is financial econometrics, option pricing, volatility modeling. During graduate education and work experience that includes both academic and industry positions he wrote research papers individually and in collaboration. Research topics include but not limited to estimation of multivariate volatity and density models, evaluation of option pricing models, geographic sources of equity risk premium, term structure of volatility risk premium, volatility forecasting. His research is regularly presented at international scientific conferences. Accompanying Python code is publicly available at GitHub repository.

CURRENT POSITION

New Economic School, Moscow, Russia

Assistant Professor of Finance

Sep 2011 – present

- Research: Conducted researh independently as well as with co-authors in the fields of financial econometrics, option pricing, volatility modelling.
 - Searched and surveyed all relevant literature on the subject. Collected, cleaned, and analyzed complex data from such sources as OptionMetrics, CRSP, TAQ, Compustat, Quandl. Collected unstructured data using web parsing methods and regular expressions. Performed Monte Carlo experiments for model selection purposes.
 - Advanced knowledge of parametric and non-parametric estimation methods of non-linear models including MLE, GMM. Implemented several models and estimation methods as Python modules publicly available from GitHub repository.
 - Presented at major international economics, finance, and econometrics conferences.
- Teaching: Intermediate Econometrics, Advanced Econometrics, Financial Econometrics, Data Analysis in Python. 10-50 students in each class.
- Supervision: 4-8 master and bachelor students each year.

Professional Experience

SAS Institute, Cary, NC

Summer technical student

May 2007 - Aug 2010

Programmed C module for estimation of GEE type models

Wrote examples of usage of new Copula procedure

Participated in writing of future publication "SAS/ETS User's Guide" Added examples of usage and edited manuals for SAS/ETS procedures

University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC

Teaching/Research assistant

Aug 2007 – May 2011

Teaching: Recitations in graduate classes: Intro to Probability Theory, Applied Econometrics, Advanced Econometrics.

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

Teaching assistant

Sep 2004 – Jul 2006

Teaching: Graduate econometrics recitations. Graded undergraduate courses in economics.

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC

PhD in Economics (major in Financial Econometrics)

Aug 2011

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

Dec 2006

Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia

BA. MA in Economics Jun 2004

Skills Operating systems: Linux, Windows

Packages: Python, MatLab, SAS (certified), C/C++ (basics), LATEX, Git

Language: English (fluent), German (A2), Russian (native)

Publications Stanislav Anatolyev and Stanislav Khrapov (2015). Right on Target, or Is it? The Role

of Distributional Shape in Variance Targeting. Econometrics, 3(3), pp. 610-632

Research Affine Option Pricing Model in Discrete Time (working paper, with Eric Renault)

Buy Global, Sell Local. Consumption Heterogeneity, Regional Risk-sharing,

and the Cross-section of Equity Returns (with Riccardo Colacito)

Option Pricing via Risk-Neutral Density Forecasting (working paper)

Pricing Central Tendency in Volatility (working paper)

Do Spatial Structures Yield Better Volatility Forecasts?

(working paper, with Stanislav Anatolyev)

Realized Skewness Predicts Jump Variation

(working paper, with Elena Buchatskaya)

Risk Premia: Short and Long-term (working paper)

Modeling Vast Dimensional Autoregressive Conditional Density

(work in progress, with Stanislav Anatolyev and Andrey Zeleneev)

Capital Structure and Equity Correlation Premiums (work in progress, with Oleg Gredil)

Presentations

2017: Vienna-Copenhagen Financial Econometrics Conference (Vienna, Austria), 4th ESSEC Empirical Finance Workshop (Cergy, France). 2016: Annual Congress of the European Economic Association and Econometric Society European Meetings (Geneva, Switzerland), 23rd International Conference "Forecasting Financial Markets" (Hanover, Germany). 2015: 2nd International Workshop on "Financial Markets and Nonlinear Dynamics" (Paris, France), 23rd Symposium of the Society for Nonlinear Dynamics and Econometrics (Oslo, Norway). 2014: International conference "Modern econometric tools and applications" (Nizhniy Novgorod, Russia), 8th International Conference on Computational and Financial Econometrics (Pisa, Italy). 2013: Humboldt-Copenhagen Financial Econometrics Conference (Berlin, Germany), Econometric Society European Meeting (Goteborg, Sweden), International Moscow Finance Conference (Moscow, 2012: Financial Management Association European Conference (Istanbul, Turkey), Society for Financial Econometrics (Oxford, Great Britain), Econometric Society European Meeting (Malaga, Spain), Financial Management Association Annual Meeting (Atlanta, USA), Econometric Society Asian Meeting (Delhi, India). 2011: Higher School of Economics (Moscow, Russia), Midwest Econometrics Group (Chicago, USA)